Raj Ranjhan

Austin,TX • (512) 710 6696 • ranjhan@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/aranjhan

Professional SUMMARY

- Strong leadership and mentoring skills; ability to prioritize and manage work in a fast-paced, multiple-project environment
- I bring over 15 years. of application development experience to designing and developing Cybersecurity solutions.
- Solid track record in Analysis, Design, and Implementation of Cloud Security Architecture (PCF, GCP, AWS)

Technical Skills

AWS Cloud EC2, EFS, ELB, ECR, EKS, Lambda, S3, Glacier, ASG, AMI, RDS, KMS, OpenSearch, CloudWatch, CloudFormation, CloudTrail, SQS, VPC, CloudFront, Route 53, WAF, API Gateway, etc.

GCP CLOUD App Engine, Compute Engine, Kubernetes/GKE, Anthos, Helm, Istio, Cloud Functions, Cloud Run, Cloud Scheduler, Buckets, VPC, Firewall, Routes, Cloud DNS, Cloud CDN, NAT, Deployment Manager, Pub/Sub, BigQuery, Dataflow, Secret Manager, Apigee, etc.

SOFTWARE Python, Terraform, SQL, HTML, CSS, XML, YAML, JSON, JS, Batch, Bash, C#

SECURITY IAM, Macie, Prisma Cloud, TwistLock, SonarQube, Okta, GuardDuty, Command Center, Cloud Armor, Vault, Veracode, Snyk, Rapid7, Qualys, etc.

EMPLOYMENT & EXPERIENCE

Charles Schwab Austin, TX

Technical Director, Principal Cloud Security Architect

August 2022-

- Grow and mature Schwab's AWS/GCP cloud security posture to support products with scalable, performant, high-availability cloud technology solutions, processes, and best practices.
- Mentor and coach team accountable for automation, operational integrity, and security of a multi-cloud infrastructure.
- Responsible for advancing and ensuring the success of Policy as a Code Initiative.

Rapid7 Austin, TX

Lead Cloud Security Architect, AWS

October 2021-August 2022

- Architected security solutions built on the AWS Platform
- Managed Infosec AWS infrastructure automation using Terraform
- Helped develop the Secure Design Review process from the ground up
- Ensure security controls are integrated as we stand up Aws GovCloud environment for FedRAMP
- Coached, mentored, and developed team members in AWS

Teradata Austin, TX

Cloud Security Architect, Cloud Incubation Team

June 2020- October 2021 Lead design and implementation of IAM strategy for a multi-tenant application in AWS

- Worked with network, platform, engineering, and development teams in architecture design and review session
- Conducted security architecture reviews across the organization and produced high-quality Threat Models for cloud environments
- Hands-on development of custom security controls in Python

Charles Schwab Austin, TX

Technical Director, Data Security Architect

June 2016- June 2020

- Architected and managed implementation of all matters relating to data security across multiple lines of business.
- Manage strategy, optimization, and implementation of data security in GCP.
- Act as a data security SME at IT Security Governance, ensuring Policies and Standards are followed during application development.
- Automated Data Activity Monitoring activities save the team over 80 monthly person-hours.
- Frameworks and standards: NIST; MITRE; CIS; CSA CCM, OWASP
- Environment: Voltage, Vormetric, Imperva, SonarG, Python, .NET

Technical Director, Web Architect

- Lead the effort to roll out the oAuth authentication flow within the SAC portal.
- Designed and developed application security solutions and training programs based on OWASP Top 10.
- Prepared and documented threat models, security diagrams, and other supporting materials.

John Hancock Boston, MA March 2012 – June 2016

Senior Innovation Fellow at Innovation Lab

- Lead a team to develop next-generation applications based on blockchain technology.
- Researched and prototyped applications on various blockchain platforms.
- Developed an internal cryptocurrency based on Bitcoin source code.

Director, Application Development Manager

Hands-on onshore and offshore development team manager responsible for implementing and expanding SOA capabilities. Business areas supported: Hedging, Derivatives, and Investments.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Security - Specialty Google Professional Cloud Security Engineer (GPCSE) Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP) CSA Certificate of Cloud Security Knowledge (CSSK)

University of Massachusetts Amherst, MA Bachelor of Science